Finding Aid for the Thomas Fensch Collection
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
Thomas Fensch Collection
Undated
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
MSS.0135
.42 linear feet
Biographical Sketch
Thomas Fensch is an author of over thirty books, mostly investigative accounts on famous authors or organizations. At the time that he gave his collection to Vanderbilt Joint Libraries in 1972, he had already written three books. He is originally from Mansfield, Ohio, where he received his high school diploma from Mansfield High in 1961. Fensch taught journalism classes at Mansfield-OSU and published multiple books before receiving his doctorate degree in journalism from Syracuse University in 1977. He currently is the Chair of the department of Mass Communications at Virginia Union University.
Scope & Contents Note
The collection contains numerous document formats all pertaining to Country and Western music. The contents date from the mid-1960s to the early 1970s, with only a few exceptions. The boxes are organized by series. The first box is an alphabetical list of subject headings, mostly names of Country and Western musicians, songwriters, and business people. The headings also include popular places associated with country music and ephemera. The documents are various photographs, newspaper and magazine clippings, and anonymously written one to five page pamphlets. The second box contains the series Country Song Roundup. The monthly publication is organized chronologically, beginning in 1968 with issues until 1971, released song lyrics from the latest Country and Western songwriters and featured short articles about famous country personalities. The third box is a miscellaneous box of publications. It includes magazines, pamphlets, and biographical-style periodical issues. The fourth and fifth boxes are an alphabetical-by-artist series of song books. Unlike the magazine issues, these songs are accompanied by the written music. The sixth box is a chronological series of Song Hits Magazine periodicals from 1970 and 1971. The publication is similar to Country Song Roundup although its title indicates that it did not only release songs from the Country and Western genre. The seventh box holds only two documents, published by Country Music Who’s Who, a publication that gives news and updates on country music personalities. One is a smaller pamphlet ranging from 1948 to 1969, while the other is a large 1970 edition text. The eighth box holds a series of loose sheet music, organized by the last name of the song’s writer. The date range is varied, with a few pieces dating from the 1950’s and most from the mid-1960’s.
- Acuff, Roy (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Anderson, Bill (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Atkins, Chet (Box 1, Folder 3)
- The Band (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Barron, Arthur and Evelyn (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Cash, Johnny (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Clement, Jack (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Country, “Hillbilly” Music (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Country Music Association (CMA) (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Davis, Skeeter (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Drake, Pete (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Faron Young & the Deputies (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Flatt, Lester & Scruggs, Earl (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Haggard, Merle (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Hee Haw (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Husky, Ferlin (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Kristofferson, Kris (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Lewis, Jerry Lee (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Moore, Connie (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Nashville (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Owens, Buck (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Pearl, Minnie (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Photographs (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Photographs (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Photographs (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Pierce, Webb (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Reeves, Jim (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Reeves, Ray (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Riley, Jeannie C. (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Walker, Bill (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Webb, Jim (Box 1, Folder 31)
- Worth, Marion (Box 1, Folder 32)
- WSM Radio (Box 1, Folder 33)
- Ephemera - Country Music Birthday Calendar, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 34)
- Publications - Country Song Roundup - Loose (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Publications - Country Song Roundup, 1968, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Publications - Country Song Roundup, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Publications - Country Song Roundup, 1969, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Publications - Country Song Roundup, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Publications - Country Song Roundup, 1970, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Publications - Country Song Roundup, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Publications - Country Song Roundup, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Publications - Country Song Roundup, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Publications - Miscellaneous - A Boy Named Cash (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Publications - Miscellaneous - Broadcast Music, Inc. (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Publications - Miscellaneous - Catalog of Country and Western Music Long Playing Records (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Publications - Miscellaneous - Classified Directory for Country Music (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Publications - Miscellaneous - Crawdaddy (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Publications - Miscellaneous - Hank Williams (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Publications - Miscellaneous - In the World of Country Music (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Publications - Miscellaneous - Johnny Cash (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Publications - Miscellaneous - Pulse Defines the Modern Country Music Audience (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Publications - Miscellaneous - Super Stars Magazine: Johnny Cash Issue (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Publications - Miscellaneous - WSM Grand Ole Opry (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Publications - Song Books - The Best of Charley Pride Song Album (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Publications - Song Books - The Best of Charley Pride Song Album (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Publications - Song Books - The Best of Loretta Lynn (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Publications - Song Books - Country Music Hits -, 1970, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Publications - Song Books - Country Special (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Publications - Song Books - Everybody’s Country (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Publications - Song Books - The Glenn Sutton & Billy Sherrill Country Song Book (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Publications - Song Books - Hee Haw (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Publications - Song Books - Songs for the Seventies (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Publications - Song Books - Songs of Johnny Cash (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Publications - Song Books - Tony Joe White (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Publications - Song Books - The Town and Country Songs of Bobby Russell (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Publications - Song Books - The Very Best of Country Music (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Publications - Song Hits Magazine, 1970 (Box 6)
- Publications - Song Hits Magazine, 1970 (Box 6, Folder 2)
- Publications - Song Hits Magazine, 1971 (Box 6, Folder 3)
- Publications - Song Hits Magazine, 1971 (Box 6, Folder 4)
- Publications - Country Music Who’s Who - Country Music News, 1948-1969 (Box 7, Folder 1)
- Publications - Country Music Who’s Who - The Country Music Who’s Who 1970 Edition (Box 7, Folder 2)
- Sheet Music - A-C (Box 8, Folder 1)
- Sheet Music - D-G (Box 8, Folder 2)
- Sheet Music - H (Box 8, Folder 3)
- Sheet Music - I (Box 8, Folder 4)
- Sheet Music - J-K (Box 8, Folder 5)
- Sheet Music - M (Box 8, Folder 6)
- Sheet Music - N-Sk (Box 8, Folder 7)
- Sheet Music - Sj-V (Box 8, Folder 8)
- Sheet Music - W-Z (Box 8, Folder 9)
- Oversize (Box 9)
  - Campbell, Glen (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Cash, Johnny (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Country Music (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Crawdaddy (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Grand Ole Opry (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Haggard, Merle (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Kristofferson, Kris (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Pride, Charlie (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - York, Willie (Box 9, Folder 9)
- Oversize (Box 10)
  - Ephemera (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Johnny Cash (Box 10, Folder 2)